Shadi Haddad

■ shhaddad@ucsc.edu | 👚 shadihdd.github.io | 🛅 shadi-haddad

SUMMARY _

PhD in applied mathematics and MSc in mechanical engineering focused on uncertain systems, machine learning, and control; a strong mathematical background in optimization and dynamical systems; and extensive programming experience implementing numerical simulations, novel neural architectures, and optimization techniques.

EDUCATION .

PhD, Applied Mathematics (uncertain systems, optimization, machine learning, and control) Sep 2019 – March 2024 University of California, Santa Cruz Santa Cruz, CA

• Applied Mathematics Research Award • Chancellor's Fellowship • Advancement with Honors

MSc, Mechanical Engineering (vibration control and mechanical design)

Sep 2015 – Jan 2018

University of Tehran

Tehran, Iran

• Full Tuition Merit Scholarship

SKILLS .

Optimization: Semidefinite Programming (SDP), Gradient-based & interior point constrained optimization.

Machine Learning: Nonlinear regression, Neural networks, Reachability analysis.

Control: Optimal control, Stochastic control, Model predictive control (MPC). Programming: Python (incl. NumPy, SciPy, Jax), MATLAB and Simulink, C++.

Software: SolidWorks, Abagus FEA, git.

EXPERIENCE _

Graduate Student Researcher

Sept 2019 - March 2024

UC Santa Cruz

Santa Cruz, CA

- Introduced the sublinear input neural network (ISNN) architecture (output function is sublinear in input data).
- Developed custom algorithms for set-based reachability, improving accuracy by 20-30% over leading methods.
- Proposed a probabilistic learning approach to estimate the reach sets of feedback linearizable systems.
- Devised novel reach set intersection detection methods for feedback linearizable systems.
- Established upper bounds for the expected Hausdorff distance between linear time varying control systems.

Team Leader

Sept 2020 – March 2022

Ford University Research Project, Ford Greenfields Lab

Palo Alto, CA

- Proposed a non-parametric stochastic prediction method with 30% runtime speedup over Monte Carlo in an automated driving highway case study.
- Designed a prediction and optimal feedback control framework for stochastic reachability in multi-lane automated driving.

Graduate Student Researcher

Sep 2015 – Jan 2018

Mechanical Engineering, University of Tehran

Tehran, Iran

- Designed micro-piezoelectric actuator and performed vibration control.
- Designed an observer-based fault reconstruction scheme using terminal sliding modes to guarantee asymptotic system convergence.
- Derived the analytical solution for a nonlinear model of a functionally graded tapered micro-bridge using Homotopy-Padé technique.
- Increased axial deflection of micro-beam by 18% and improved model of natural frequency by considering small scale effects, nonlinear mid-plane stretching, and lateral deflections.

PUBLICATIONS

Exact Computation of LTI Reach Set from Integrator Reach Set with Bounded Input.

Shadi Haddad, Pansie Khodary, Abhishek Halder. IEEE Control Systems Letters, 2024, URL.

The Curious Case of Integrator Reach Sets, Part I: Basic Theory.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, 2023, URL.

Convex and Nonconvex Sublinear Regression with Application to Data-driven Learning of Reach Sets.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. American Control Conference, 2023, URL.

A note on the Hausdorff Distance between Norm Balls and their Linear Maps.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. Set-Valued and Variational Analysis, 2023, URL.

Certifying the Intersection of Reach Sets of Integrator Agents with Set-valued Input Uncertainties.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. IEEE Control Systems Letters, 2022, URL.

Density-Based Stochastic Reachability Computation for Occupancy Prediction in Automated Driving.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder, and Baljeet Singh. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2022, URL.

Boundary and Taxonomy of Integrator Reach Sets.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. American Control Conference, 2022, URL.

Anytime Ellipsoidal Over-approximation of Forward Reach Sets of Uncertain Linear Systems.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. CPS IoT Week Workshop, 2021, URL.

Prediction and Optimal Feedback Steering of Probability Density Functions for Safe Automated Driving.

Shadi Haddad, Kenneth F Caluya, Abhishek Halder, Baljeet Singh. IEEE Control Systems Letters, 2020, URL.

The Convex Geometry of Integrator Reach Sets.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. American Control Conference, 2020, URL.

Observer Based Fault Reconstruction Schemes Using Terminal Sliding Modes.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. International Journal of Control, 2018, URL.

Analytical Study on Nonlinear 3D Coupled Deformations of Tapered FG Micro-beams Accounting for Size Effects.

Shadi Haddad, Abhishek Halder. Iranian Journal of Science and Technology, 2018, URL.

HONORS & AWARDS

Applied Mathematics Research Award.

University of California at Santa Cruz, 2022.

Student Travel Award.

IEEE Control Systems Society, American Control Conference, 2020-2022.

Advancement to Ph.D Candidacy with Honors.

University of California at Santa Cruz, 2022.

Chancellor's Fellowship.

University of California at Santa Cruz, 2019.

Full Tuition Merit Scholarship.

University of Tehran, 2015.

Ranked top 1% among more than 20,000 applicants in nationwide universities entrance exam for Mechanical Engineering graduate studies.

Iran, 2015.

Ranked top 1% among more than 340,000 applicants in nationwide universities entrance exam for undergraduate studies. *Iran*, 2011.